# RANDY TATE JR.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# PERSONAL PROFILE

Passionate about learning, personal growth, leaving a positive legacy, my family, sports, and enjoying life as much as possible.

My 7-year career as a Technical Recruiter has allowed me to peek into the world of software development and has ultimately allowed me to realize I genuinely enjoy the challenges and victories it presents. I enrolled in Nashville Software School to create a solid foundational base in which I can continue my journey within the field.

# CONNECT WITH ME

Cell: (615) 692-4001 Email: randytatejr@gmail.com Portfolio: randytatejr.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/randytatejr GitHub: github.com/rtate2

# INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS

## I GOT NEXT

An app that allows recreational basketball players to organize and manage the sign-up waitlist sheet. I GOT NEXT addresses the issues of maintaining a consistent list of players/teams and order in which the games will be played. Built using REACT, Bootstrap, Firebase, and

https://github.com/rtate2/i-got-next

# TECHNOLOGIES

- VS Code
- Git/GitHub
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and SCSS
- JavaScript, ES6 modules, and jQuery
- ReactJS and React Routing
- Postman
- · Firebase, JSON, Promises, and Axios
- C# and Visual Studio
- ASP.NET Core and APIs
- · T-SQL and MS SQL Server Managemnet Studio

## EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate Nashville Software School, 2019 - Present

Masters of Arts in Education Cumberland University, 2012

Bachelors of Arts, Sport Management University of Tennessee, Knoxville, 2008

# EXPERIENCE

## FRONT END DEVELOPER

#### Nashville Software School

August 2019 - Present

"One year part-time bootcamp that equips students with the necessary skills to become full-stack software developers through hands-on training"

- Build single page apps using HTML, Sass, Bootstrap, ES6 JavaScript, and
- Utilize GitHub for source code version control and group collaboration
- Create and deploy full CRUD applications using Firebase
- · Learned backend technologies: C#, ASP.Net Core, Databases and SQL

#### **GROUP PROJECTS**

#### Star Destroyer

An app which allows the user to view the Star Destroyer Database and its content. When logged in as a member of the Galactic Empire, via Google Authentication, you can modify the Star Destroyer's database contents using CRUD components on each page.

- Directly responsible for full CRUD on the mission personnel
- Utilized JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, and Firebase
- Participated in stand-ups to discuss progress and current barriers during this project
  - https://nutshell-star-destoyer.firebaseapp.com/
  - https://github.com/nss-evening-cohort-10/nutshell-star-destroyer

#### PANAM AIRLINES

A deployed MVP of the once PanAm Airline company. An internal system application used to maintain the crew, airport, food services, and fleet tracking.

- Completed full CRUD on the 'Flight Crew' for the app using Firebase and JavaScript
- Set up user authentication with Firebase and Google ensuring users could only see content unique to their account
- Utilized JavaScript, SCSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, and Firebase
  - https://nutshell-panam.firebaseapp.com/
  - https://github.com/nss-evening-cohort-10/nutshell-panam-airlines

### SENIOR TECHNICAL RECRUITER / ACCOUNT MANAGER

Staffing as a Mission - Nashville. TN

May 2016 - Present

- Started as Recruiter and within the first 3 months, promoted to Sr.
- ttps://i-got-next-frontend-capstone.firebaseapp.com/home Lead/sole recruiter for developing the SaaM IT division which focused on recruiting technical professionals nationwide.
  - Promoted to Account Manager within the SaaM IT division which allowed me to begin working with hiring managers directly.
  - Produced \$1M+ in revenue in 2018 as the top recruiter in the company
  - Skills used daily include Talent Assessment, Offer Negotiation, Client Relationship Management, ATS & Recruiting software, etc.

## SENIOR TECHNICAL RECRUITER

## ConsultNet, LLC - South Jordan, UT

August 2014 - April 2016

- · Remotely sourced, screened, interviewed, and evaluated IT professionals and placed with clients primarily in Utah, as well as nationally.
- Exercised consistent communication and career guidance to candidates by utilizing phone, email and video teleconferencing tools.
- · Selected as a recruiter to work on one the company's biggest accounts due to my success recruiting technical professionals

## SENIOR TECHNICAL RECRUITER

Robert Half Technology - Nashville, TN

October 2012 - July 2014

- · Began career as a Technical Recruiter and was promoted to Sr. Technical Recruiter due to meeting/exceeding recruiting metrics while positively affecting the bottom-line.
- · Member of a high-performing team which exceeded team goals consistently, and personally contributed by meeting/exceeding the recruiter metrics which included 10+ candidate interviews weekly, setting up qualified candidates with client interviews and getting them hired.